Inventory of the Paul N. McCloskey papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul N. McCloskey papers
1967-1983
82112
Hoover Institution Archives
631 cubic foot boxes, 55 manuscript boxes (653.0 linear feet)
Consists of the congressional papers maintained by Paul (Pete) McCloskey's staff at his Washington, D.C., office and California district office while McCloskey was a member of the U.S. House of Representatives from 1967 to 1983. The papers relate to many aspects of American foreign relations and domestic politics, the 1972 Presidential election, and the Vietnam War, and consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
McCloskey, Paul N., 1927-
Access
Boxes 611-651 closed. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Chronology
1927 September 29 Born, Loma Linda, California
1945-1947 Served in U.S. Navy
1950 B.A., Stanford University
1950-1952 Served in U.S. Marine Corps
1953 Stanford University Law School
1953-1954 Deputy district attorney, Alameda County, California
1955-1967 Attorney, private practice, Palo Alto, California
1964 Author, The United States Constitution
1964-1967 Lecturer on legal ethics, Santa Clara University and Stanford University Law Schools
1967-1983 Member, U.S. House of Representatives (90th - 97th Congresses)
1972 Author, Truth and Untruth; Political Deceit in America Republican candidate for president (primary election)
1982 Republican candidate for U.S. Senate (primary election)
1988-1994 Lecturer on legal ethics, Santa Clara University and Stanford University Law Schools
2006 Republican candidate, primary election, California 11th Congressional District
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of the congressional papers maintained by Paul (Pete) McCloskey's staff at his Washington, D.C., office and California district office while McCloskey was a member of the U.S. House of Representatives from 1967 to 1983. The papers relate to many aspects of American foreign relations and domestic politics, the 1972 Presidential election, and the Vietnam War, and consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter.
McCloskey was a member of the Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee, the Government Operations Committee, and the Select Committee on Missing Persons in Southeast Asia.
One major series, the Subject File, contains most of the constituent correspondence on legislative issues, with related materials. McCloskey's staff used several different filing systems for the Subject File. Initially the files were arranged alphabetically by subject term. This was replaced by a file system that used letters of the alphabet to indicate general subjects, which were then followed by a more specific subject term. For example, "J" represented the environment, and specific subjects like "air pollution" and "national parks" were filed under file code "J." This system of alpha file codes was in use from about 1971 to 1976. Some file codes remained the same each year, while other file codes changed. "J" always represented "environment," whereas "A" represented "grants and contracts" in 1972 and "17th district" in 1973.
In 1977 the alpha file code system was replaced by a numeric file code system in which numbers represented subjects. For example, "21000" represented "environment" and "22000" represented "federal government." Specific subjects within the general subject "environment" received numbers from 21000 to 21999, such as "21107--Environment--Lake Tahoe." Numeric file codes were used through 1983. Unlike the previous alpha file codes, the bulk of the numeric file codes represented the same subject through their years of use.
In the container list, most of the Subject File listings provide only the first and last folder in the box. In most cases, file codes that occur within the sequence of first and last file codes will also be found in that box. For example, the listing of 1971 alpha file codes, "K--San Mateo County" to "M--Transportation--Trucking" also includes all of the "L--Law enforcement" files because "L" is between "K" and "M." As another example, with the numeric files, the sequence of folders from "16070--Congress--Pensions" to "21040--Environment--Clean Air Act--General statement" includes file codes between 16070 and 21040, including "17000--Crime and justice" and "20000--Energy," among others.
General file codes for the Subject File are provided below. More detailed file plans are available at the Hoover Institution. The more detailed file plans help locate some files that may not have been filed in the most intuitive manner. For example, "abortion" was assigned to alpha file code "J--Environment" from at least 1971 to 1973; by 1975 it had moved to "H--HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare)."
File Plan
Classification schemes used for arranging, storing, and retrieving materials created by McCloskey's staff at his Washington, D.C. office and California district office.
Alpha file codes, 1971
A--Appropriations
B--Business
C--California
D--Defense
E--Economy
F--Foreign affairs
H--HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare)
I--Congress
J--Environment
K--San Mateo County
L--Law enforcement
M--Transportation
N--Activities
0--Publications
P--DURAs (refers to the computerized form letter response system)
Q--Academies
R--Office
S--Invitations
T--PNM (P. N. McCloskey) personal
W--Names
X--Casework
Y--Grants
Z--Political
Alpha file codes, 1972
A--Grants and contracts
B--San Mateo County
C--California
D--Defense
E--Economy
F--Foreign affairs
G--Government
H--HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare)
I--Transportation
J--Environment
K--Sea war
L--Law enforcement
M--DURAs (refers to the computerized form letter response system)
N--Names
0--Activities
P--Publications
Q--Academies
R--Office
S--Invitations
T--PNM (P. N. McCloskey) personal
U--Political
V--Press
X--Casework
Alpha file codes, 1973
A--17th District
C--California
D--Defense
E--Economy
F--Foreign affairs
G--Government
H--HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare)
I--Transportation
J--Environment
L--Law enforcement
M--DURAs (refers to the computerized form letter response system)
N--Names
0--Activities
P--Requests
Q--Academies
R--Office
S--Invitations
T--PNM (P. N. McCloskey) personal
U--Political
V--Press
X--Casework
Alpha file codes, 1975
A--District
B--Energy
C--California
D--Defense
E--Economy
F--Foreign affairs
G--Government
H--HEW (Department of Health, Education and Welfare)
I--Transportation
J--Environment
L--Law enforcement
M--DURAs (refers to the computerized form letter response system)
N--Names
0--Office
P--Political
Q--Academies
R--Requests
S--Invitations
T--PNM (P. N. McCloskey) personal
V--Press
X--Casework
Numeric file codes, 1977-1982
07010--General correspondence
07050--Condolence letter
07100--Congratulations
07145--District office correspondence
07150--Employment inquiry
07200--Intern inquiry
07250--Invitations/Scheduling
07300--Equipment/Orders
07350--Recommendation
07400--Referral letter (out of district)
07450--Requests
07500--Thank you
08500--Washington visitor
08600--Department files/Casework--Academies
08785--Department files/Casework--Federal/State agencies and private organizations
10000--Aging
10500--Agriculture
11000--Animal welfare
11500--Arts
11510--Copyright general
12000--Banking and currency
13000--Business
14000--Civil rights
15000--Communications
16000--Congress
16500--Consumers
17000--Crime and justice
17500--Defense
18500--Economy and budget
19500--Education
20000--Energy
21000--Environment
22000--Federal government
22500--Health
23500--Housing
23550--Immigration
24000--Indians
24500--International relations
25500--Labor
26500--Merchant Marine and Fisheries
27000--Missing in Action Select Committee
27210--Population information
27500--Postal Service
28000--Religion
28500--Social Security
29000--Space exploration
29500--Taxes
30500--Trade
31000--Transportation
31500--Veterans
31600--Welfare (see also 32000)
32000--Inactive files/Welfare
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
United States. Congress. House.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Statesmen--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
- Washington, D.C. office (Box 1)
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file, circa 1975
    - Law of the sea treaty--Background
    - 200-mile fisheries jurisdiction
    - Deep seabed minerals
  - Miscellany, 1969-1980 (Box 2)
    - Stanislaus River
    - Restitution and criminal justice
    - Reconciliation bill
    - Greenpeace book
    - Press miscellany and notes
    - Department of the Army--Cyanamid Company, 1973
    - Biography re-write
    - Vietnam--Background materials, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file (Box 4)
    - Code of conduct for liner conferences
    - Inter-Governmental Maritime Consultative Organization Assembly
    - Great Lakes-Seaway port development and shipper conference
  - Miscellany, 1973-1980
    - Omnibus regulatory
    - Defense appropriation bill
    - FMC reorganization
    - Commerce transition
    - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) extension
    - Nixon--Watergate (Box 5)
    - Nixon-Hughes tool loan
    - Milk price support documents
    - Haldeman deposition
    - Presidential taped conversations
    - Taft-Schreiber-Nixon political dealings with film industry, 1974
    - Impeachment debates (Box 6)
    - Agnew investigation
    - Nixon campaign activities
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file, 1975-1979 (Box 7)
    - Panama Canal
    - Merchant marine oversight hearings
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file, 1974-1982 (Box 8)
    - Panama Canal
    - International Whaling Commission
    - Code of conduct for liner conferences, 1974
    - Draft letter to Andrew Gibson regarding maritime policy
  - Miscellany. In defense of deregulation of natural gas
  - Miscellany, 1974-1979 (Box 9)
    - U.S. nuclear policy, 1976
    - Energy policy, 1976
    - Hearst kidnapping
    - Nuclear Fuel Assistance Act
    - Energy/Sierra Club, 1979
    - Nuclear power positions, 1978
    - Gasoline details, 1979
  - Voting records, 1968-1982 (Box 10)
  - Miscellany, 1969-1975 (Box 11)
    - Vietnam
    - Postal Service information and legislation
  - Miscellany, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
    - Vietnam and Cambodia--Background materials and maps
    - Nixon
  - Miscellany, 1968-1971 (Box 13)
    - Laos bombing
    - Vietnam documents
    - Leadership
    - Postal Service
    - Civil service reform
    - Vietnam drafts
    - Tax administration
  - Miscellany, 1973-1975 (Box 14)
    - Vietnam trip, (1975)
    - Survey of Vietnam attitudes
    - Vietnam materials. (Box 15)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes information regarding prisoners of war (POWs), Fulbright correspondence on Pentagon Papers
  - Miscellany, 1972-1976 (Box 16)
    - Marine Mammal Act, (1972)
    - Merchant Marine Academy
    - Anti-ballistic missile (ABM)
    - Vietnam
  - Miscellany, 1967-1973 (Box 17)
    - Voting record, 1967
    - Wednesday Group
    - Ripon Society
    - Members of Congress for Peace through Law
    - Shrimp fishing--Brazil, H.R. 8529
    - Government Operations--93rd Congress
    - Parents Magazine book, Systems of Government
    - Ditchley conference
    - 8-66 Club, 1973
    - 90th Club, 1973
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file
    - General, 1973
    - Sea grant
    - Merchant marine studies, 1976-1979 (Box 18)
    - Fisheries and wildlife animals, 1976-1979
  - Miscellany, 1976-1979
    - Catalog of all Federal assistance programs, 1979
    - Impeachment of Nixon
    - Radloff
    - Mag card letters, 1976
  - Miscellany, 1968-1972 (Box 19)
    - Environment
    - Pan Am
    - Government operations
    - Earthquakes
    - Teacher corps
    - Taxes
    - Arthur Wells relief
    - Inauguration, 1969
    - Financial records, 1971-1972
    - District office administrative records, ca. 1968-1972
  - Letters sent (pink copies). Alphabetical by name of correspondent (Box 20)
    - A - Me, 1969
  - Miscellany, 1968-1970 (Box 21)
    - Atkinson ships file
    - Earth Resources and Population Task Force, 1970
    - Congressional reform
    - Labor Law Reform Task Force, 1969-1970
    - Dirty dozen
    - Members of Congress for Peace through Law
    - Wednesday Club
    - Presidential classroom for young Americans
    - Close-up
    - 90th Club
    - Government Operations, 1969-1970
    - AID investigation, 1968
    - Nuclear Power Plant Site, 1968
    - Reorganization Plan No. 1, 1968
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file. Merchant marine, fish, and wildlife records, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Committee on Government Operations file. Conservation and reorganization plans, 1970
  - Letters sent (pink copies) (Box 23)
    - Moa - Z, 1969
    - A - Str, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Sponsor/Cosponsor bill file. (Box 25)
    Copies of bills, correspondence, and background material, for bills sponsored or cosponsored by McCloskey
    - H.R. 7366 - H.R. 15226 (with gaps), and various resolutions, etc., 1969
  - Letters sent (pink copies). A - Z, 1970 (Box 26)
  - Sponsor/Cosponsor bill file. H.R. 220 - H.R. 19916 (with gaps), and various resolutions, etc., 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Miscellany (Box 28)
    - Anti-war correspondence from out of the district, 1971-1972
      - Alabama - Ohio
      - Foreign
      - Armed forces post offices
      - Washington, D.C.
  - Subject file (alpha file codes). Correspondence and other materials (Box 29)
    - "Y--Grants" to "Z--Political--Common Cause,", 1969-1972
  - Miscellany, 1969-1972
    - Political files--Administrative
    - Environmental teach-in
    - San Francisco Local Development Corporation
    - Leland Murphy estate tax
    - Awareness house funding
    - Low income people data
    - Fishing industry
    - Isla Vista report
    - URS dial-a-bus application
    - Flood insurance
    - Roy Seagraves law enforcement
    - IRS Ruling 64-221 to be amended
    - Raven Enterprises
    - Florida clippings
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 30)
    - "F--Foreign affairs--State Department" to "H--HEW (Housing, Education, and Welfare)--Food stamps,", 1971
  - Miscellany. Southeast Asia war correspondence, 1971
  - Letters sent (pink copies). A - Y, 1971 January - June (Box 31)
  - Office file. Invitations rejected, 1971 July - 1972 June (Box 32)
  - Letters sent (pink copies). A - Z, 1971 June - December (Box 33)
  - Government Operations Committee file. Full committee and Subcommittee on Conservation and Natural Resources, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Miscellany, 1971
    - 90th Club
    - Wednesday Club
    - Members of Congress for Peace through Law, 1971
    - Impeachment documents
    - Dr. McGahn material
- Washington, D.C. office (Box 35)
  - Government Operations Committee file, 1971
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file (Box 36)
    - Ocean dumping, 1975
    - Mammals, 1975
    - Oil spills, 1975
    - Cargo preference, 1975
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 37)
    - "H--HEW (Housing, Education and Welfare)--Medicine" to "J--Environment--Solid waste,", 1971
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 38)
    - "K--San Mateo County" to "M--Transportation--Trucking,", 1971
    - "P--DURAs,", 1971.
      Form letters from "B:Business" to "Z:Impeachment," Laos trip, etc. DURAs refers to the computerized form letter response system
    - "A--Appropriations" to "D--Defense--Volunteer army,", 1971 (Box 39)
    - "E--Economy--Banking" to "F--Foreign affairs--POWs (prisoners of war) and Southeast Asia war,", 1971 (Box 40)
  - Office file, 1971 (Box 41)
    - Invitations accepted
    - Personal--General correspondence
    - Thanks sent
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 42)
    - "D--Distributed,", 1971
    - "N--Activities" to "W--Names,", 1971
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file (Box 43)
    - Whaling, 1979-1980
    - Whaling, 1978-1982 (Box 44)
    - Klamath Indians--Indian fishing rights, 1980-1981 (Box 45)
    - Klamath Indians--Indian fishing rights, 1978-1979 (Box 46)
    - Klamath Indians--Indian fishing rights, 1979-1981 (Box 47)
    - Klamath Indians--Indian fishing rights, 1979-1980 (Box 48)
    - Klamath Indians--Indian fishing rights, 1978-1979 (Box 49)
  - Staff members' files--Ron Losch (Box 50)
    - Merchant marine files, 1977-1981
    - Merchant marine files, 1975-1979 (Box 51)
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 52)
    - "X--Casework,", 1971
    - "T--PNM (P.N. McCloskey) personal--Boy Scouts,", 1971
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file
    - Whaling, 1971
    - Merchant marine training ship proposal, 1971
  - Miscellany
    - Immigration 92/1
    - GSA free flow packaging
    - MD responses
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 53)
    - "Labor--General" to "Treasury, Department of,", 1968
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file. Fishing streams bill, 1971-1973 (Box 54)
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 55)
    - "F--Conservation" to "I--Education--Family life education,", 1970
    - "X--Casework--Contracts" to "Y--Grants,", 1970 (Box 56)
  - Casework. Correspondence and other material (Box 57)
    - Immigration, servicemen and veterans, selective service, social security, IRS, and other cases (90/2), 1968
    - Immigration, servicemen and veterans, selective service, IRS, employment, welfare and retirement (91/1), 1969 (Box 58)
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 59)
    - "O--Health and welfare" to "Q--Law enforcement--Civil rights,", 1970
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 60)
    - "San Francisco International Airport" to "Welfare,", 1970
  - Miscellany
    - Form letters, 1970
    - Office administrative files, 1970 (Box 61)
    - Academies, 1967-1970.
      Includes Annapolis, West Point, Merchant Marine and Air Force Academies
    - Environmental teach-in, 1970
    - Form letters and mailing lists
  - Sponsor/Cosponsor bill file. H.R. 8044 - H.R. 19991 (with gaps), and various resolutions, etc. (90th Congress) (Box 62)
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject)
    - "Veterans affairs" to "Youth,", 1968
  - Office file. Invitations accepted, 1968
  - Printed matter (Box 63)
    - Congressional Record reprints
      - "Agreement of the Cessation of Hostilities in Vietnam, July 20, 1954,", 1969 December 4
      - Declare war, 1969 October 23 (Box 64)
      - Vietnam policy, 1970 March 13
      - Impeachment--Associate justice Supreme Court, 1970 April 21
      - Vietnam, 1969 December 1
    - "Statement by Paul N. McCloskey--Candidate for Congress,", 1967 September 12 (Box 65)
    - McCloskey newsletter, 1971 February. (Box 66)
      Includes "Constitutional Confrontation between Congress and the President Relative to Laos," from Congressional Record
  - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee file (Box 67)
    - Rivers for consideration in Natural Streams Fishing Act, 1970-1972
    - California water files, 1979-1981 (Box 68)
  - Voting records, 1977-1981 (Box 69)
  - Miscellany. Position letters
  - Miscellany (Box 70)
    - Questionnaire on taxes completed and returned by constituents, 1972
    - Questionnaire on taxes completed and returned by constituents, 1972 (Box 71)
    - Questionnaire on taxes completed and returned by constituents, 1972 (Box 72)
    - Questionnaire on taxes completed and returned by constituents, 1972 (Box 73)
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 74)
    - "ABAG (Association of Bay Area Governments)" to "Justice, Dept. of,", 1968
  - Miscellany (Box 75)
    - Administrative office files
    - Academies--Not nominated, 1968-1969
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 76)
    - "J--Environment--Abortions" to "J--Environment--Teach-in,", 1970
  - Office file (Box 77)
    - Invitations accepted, 1970
    - Personal--General correspondence, 1970
    - Administrative files, 1970
- Washington, D.C. office (Box 78)
  - Legislation file. "Judiciary--S. 2516 Open Housing Bill--Anti" to "Ways and Means,", 1968
  - Miscellany. Questionnaires, 1968
  - Speeches--McCloskey, 1968
  - Campaign/Political file. "Advisory groups" to "Volunteers,", 1970 (Box 79)
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 80)
    - "Foreign affairs" to "Labor,", 1969
    - "Agriculture, Department of" to "Defense Department,", 1969 (Box 81)
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 82)
    - "R--Public activities" to "V--Transportation--FAA (Federal Aviation Administration),", 1970
  - Legislation file (Box 83)
    - "Agriculture" to "Judiciary--Eighteen-year-old vote,", 1968
    - 91st Congress (Box 84)
      - "Agriculture" to "Judiciary--Eighteen-year-old vote,", 1968-1969
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 85)
    - "V--Transportation--Coast Guard" to "W--Names--Congressmen,", 1970
  - Casework, 1970.
    Servicemen and veterans (S&V), immigration (91/2)
  - Office file (Box 86)
    - Invitations accepted, 1969
    - Visitors, 1970
    - Administrative files
    - McCloskey--Personal (General), 1969
    - McCloskey--Correspondence with congressmen, 1969
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 87)
    - "Labor Department" to "Recommendations,", 1969
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 88)
    - "A--Business and labor" to "E--Congress--Referrals,", 1970
  - Printed matter (Box 89)
    - Hearings and report of Committee on Americans Missing in Southeast Asia, 1975-1976
    - McCloskey newsletters, 1969 April - 1970 May
    - Fact sheet on maritime industry and H.R. 1037, Cargo Preference Act, 1978
    - Congressional Record reprints of McCloskey activities (Box 89)
      - 1971, February 18 and September 23
      - 1976, April 12
      - 1977, January 11, March 30, September 16, and October 4
    - "Dear Colleague" letters concerning cargo preference, 1977, September 23 and October 13
    - Testimony of McCloskey concerning Renegotiation Board, 1978 April 11
    - Dear constituent letter concerning consumer protection agency, 1977 June 10
    - National debate topics for high schools reports, 1976-1977
      - Criminal justice system, 1976-1977
      - Energy policy, 1978-1979
  - Subject file (no file codes, alphabetical by subject) (Box 90)
    - "Defense, Department of," to "Foreign affairs--Korea,", 1969
  - Subject file (alpha file codes) (Box 91)
    - "S--Publications--Agricultural yearbooks" to "S--Publications--Infant care,", 1970
  - Legislation file (Box 92)
    - 91st Congress
      - "Judiciary" to "Ways and Means,", 1969
  - Casework, 1969. (Box 93)
    Servicemen and veterans, immigration, Presidio of San Francisco court martial, national cemeteries, Spanish Turkeyfoot Mine, Naval Radiological Defense Lab, Palo Alto VA Hospital women's quarters, HEW (Housing, Education and Welfare) grants--Schumacher